<?xml version='1.0'?>
<!DOCTYPE book PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "User_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>

<section id="Components_top">
	<title>"Components" View</title>
	<para>In this view, the components installed in SLEE are shown, grouped by their types. It is possible to view the components, their details and search for specific components.</para>

	<section id="Components_details">
		<title>View Components Details</title>

		<para>In the <guilabel>Browse Components</guilabel> tab a list of components is shown, grouped by their type. When clicking on one of the Component Types, a list of the available components of that type is shown, identified by their Name, Vendor and Version. If one of this components is clicked, it's details are shown. The following component types and details are available:</para>

		<para>The following details are common to all component types:</para>
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>Name</para>
				<para>The SLEE component Name identifier.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>ID</para>
				<para>The SLEE component identifier, built from the component type, name, vendor and version.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Vendor</para>
				<para>The SLEE component Vendor identifier.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Version</para>
				<para>The SLEE component Version identifier.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Source</para>
				<para>The path to the jar containing this component, inside the deployable unit jar.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Deployable Unit</para>
				<para>The deployable unit used to deploy this component.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Library References</para>
				<para>The libraries this component refers, if any.</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>

		<para>The following are specific to each component type:</para>
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>Event Type</para>
				<itemizedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para>Event Class Name</para>
						<para>The class name for this event type.</para>
					</listitem>
				</itemizedlist>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Profile Specification</para>
				<itemizedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para>CMP Interface Name</para>
						<para>The interface name for the Profile CMP.</para>
					</listitem>
				</itemizedlist>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>SBB</para>
				<itemizedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para>Address Profile Specification</para>
						<para>The profile specification to be used as the Address Profile Specification for this SBB.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Event Types</para>
						<para>The event types referenced by this SBB, either for Fire and/or Receive.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Profile Specifications</para>
						<para>The profile specs referenced by this SBB.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Resource Adaptor Entity Links</para>
						<para>The resource adaptor links required by this SBB.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Resource Adaptor Types</para>
						<para>The resource adaptor types referenced by this SBB, either for Fire and/or Receive.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>SBBs</para>
						<para>The child SBBs this SBB has.</para>
					</listitem>
					<!-- TODO: View Associated Activity Contexts -->
				</itemizedlist>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Resource Adaptor Type</para>
				<itemizedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para>Event Types</para>
						<para>The event types referenced by this Resource Adaptor Type, that it can fire.</para>
					</listitem>
				</itemizedlist>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Resource Adaptor</para>
				<itemizedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para>Event Types</para>
						<para>The Resource Adaptor Type implemented by this Resource Adaptor.</para>
					</listitem>
				</itemizedlist>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Service</para>
				<itemizedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para>Address Profile Table</para>
						<para>The Address Profile Table name to be used by this service, if any.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Resource Info Profile Table</para>
						<para>The Resource Info Profile Table name to be used by this service, if any.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Root SBB</para>
						<para>The SBB to be used as the Root SBB for this service.</para>
					</listitem>
				</itemizedlist>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Library</para>
				<itemizedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para>Library Jars</para>
						<para>The JARs exposed by this Library component.</para>
					</listitem>
				</itemizedlist>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
	</section>

	<section id="Components_search">
		<title>Search Components</title>

		<para>In order to find specific components, use the <guilabel>Search</guilabel> tab, where it is possible to specify a string to search for and click the <guibutton>Search</guibutton> button to list the components for which the name matches the given string.</para>
	
		<important>
			<title>Regular Expression not supported in Component Search</title>
			<para>When searching for components, it is not possible to use regular expressions. So using "diam*" may not return anything, while "diameter" may return something.</para>
		</important>
	</section>

</section>
