<?xml version='1.0'?>
<!DOCTYPE book PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "User_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>

<section id="SLEE">
	<title>"<acronym>SLEE</acronym>" View</title>
	<para>In this view, it is possible to view the ID of the server, such as name, vendor, version and codename and also the <acronym>SLEE</acronym> state. The following states can be observed:
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para><literal>STOPPED</literal></para>
				<para>The <acronym>SLEE</acronym> environment is configured and initialized, ready to be started. This means resource adaptor objects for resource adaptor entities in the <literal>ACTIVE</literal> state are loaded and initialized, and <acronym>SBB</acronym>s corresponding to Services in the <literal>ACTIVE</literal> state are loaded and ready to be instantiated. However the entire event-driven subsystem is idle. Resource adaptor entities and the <acronym>SLEE</acronym> are not actively producing events, and the event router is not operating. <acronym>SBB</acronym> entities are not created in this state.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><literal>STARTING</literal></para>
				<para>Any vendor-specific starting state tasks may be performed here. Services in the <literal>ACTIVE</literal> state are made ready to receive events, but <acronym>SBB</acronym> entities are still not created in this state. The <acronym>SLEE</acronym> spontaneously moves out of this state when (a) startup tasks are complete, which causes transition to the <literal>RUNNING</literal> state; (b) some startup task fails, which causes transition to the <literal>STOPPING</literal> state.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><literal>RUNNING</literal></para>
				<para>Resource adaptor objects that are in the <literal>ACTIVE</literal> (or <literal>STOPPING</literal>) state are actively firing events as conditions dictate. The <acronym>SLEE</acronym> may also be firing events. The event router is instantiating <acronym>SBB</acronym> entities and delivering events to them as required.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><literal>STOPPING</literal></para>
				<para>This state is identical to the <literal>RUNNING</literal> state except no new Activity objects are accepted by the <acronym>SLEE</acronym> from resource adaptor objects, and no new Activity objects are created by the SLEE. If this state is reached from the <literal>STARTING</literal> state, there will be no Activity objects and transition to the <literal>STOPPED</literal> state should immediately occur. If this state is reached from the <literal>RUNNING</literal> state, any existing Activity objects are allowed to end (subject to an arbitrary vendor-specified timeout). Once all Activity objects generated by a particular resource adaptor entity have ended, resource adaptor objects of that resource adaptor entity transition to the <literal>INACTIVE</literal> state. The <acronym>SLEE</acronym> transitions out of the <literal>STOPPING</literal> state once all Activity objects have ended and all resource adaptor objects have transitioned to the <literal>INACTIVE</literal> state.</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
	</para>

	<para>It is also possible to manage the <acronym>SLEE</acronym> state from this view, by using the following buttons: 
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para><guibutton>Start</guibutton></para>
				<para>In order to use this button the <acronym>SLEE</acronym> must be in the <literal>STOPPED</literal> state. It will move the <acronym>SLEE</acronym> to the <literal>STARTING</literal> state and once the start operations complete, switch to the <literal>RUNNING</literal> state.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><guibutton>Stop</guibutton></para>
				<para>In order to use this button the <acronym>SLEE</acronym> must be in the <literal>STARTED</literal> state. It will move the <acronym>SLEE</acronym> to the <literal>STOPING</literal> state and once the stop operations complete, switch to the <literal>STOPPED</literal> state.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><guibutton>Shutdown</guibutton></para>
				<para>In order to use this button the <acronym>SLEE</acronym> must be in the <literal>STOPPED</literal> state. It will shutdown completely the <acronym>SLEE</acronym> container as well as the &JEE.PLATFORM;.</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
	</para>
</section>
