<?xml version='1.0'?>
<!DOCTYPE book PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "User_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>

<section id="Alarms_top">
	<title>"Alarms" View</title>

	<para>
		<figure>
			<title>Alarms Main View</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata width="100%" align="center" fileref="images/img-smc-Alarms-main-view.png" format="PNG"/>
				</imageobject>
				<textobject>
					<para>The Alarms Main View, showing the existing Alarms, and an action link for clearing each.</para>
				</textobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>
	</para>

	<para>In this view, it's possible to monitor the alarms which occured in the SLEE. The alarms are listed by their Timestamp, ID, Level and Message.</para>

	<note>
		<title>No automatic refresh</title>
		<para>In order to keep a low impact on the SLEE no real-time update is performed with regards to the Usage Parameters. To update the displayed values, please click the <guibutton>refresh</guibutton> link.</para>
	</note>

	<section id="Alarms_details">
		<title>View Alarms Details</title>

		<para>
			<figure>
				<title>Alarms Details View</title>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata width="100%" align="center" fileref="images/img-smc-Alarms-alarm-details.png" format="PNG"/>
					</imageobject>
					<textobject>
						<para>The Alarms Details View, showing the details of a selected alarm.</para>
					</textobject>
				</mediaobject>
			</figure>
		</para>

		<para>In the <guilabel>Active Alarms</guilabel> tab the list of alarms is shown. When clicking on one of the alarms ID, it's details are shown. The following details are displayed:</para>

		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>ID</para>
				<para>The internal identifier for this alarm.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Timestamp</para>
				<para>The Java class representing this activity.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Level</para>
				<para>The alarm level of the alarm represented by the alarm notification. In order of severity, from highest to least, they are: CLEAR, CRITICAL, MAJOR, WARNING, INDETERMINATE, MINOR.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Type</para>
				<para>The alarm type of the generated alarm, set by the alarm source.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Instance</para>
				<para>The instance of the generated alarm, set by the alarm source.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Message</para>
				<para>The message of the alarm notification.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Cause</para>
				<para>The Throwable which caused this alarm to be raised, if any, typically used to propagate an exception in the alarm notification.</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
	</section>

	<section id="Alarms_clear">
		<title>Clear an Alarm</title>

		<para>It is possible to clear an alarm by clicking the <guibutton>clear</guibutton> button in the list view or by clicking the <guibutton>Clear alarm</guibutton> button in the details view of an alarm.</para>
	</section>

</section>
