<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!DOCTYPE book PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "User_Guide.ent">%BOOK_ENTITIES;]><chapter id="introduction">	<title>		Introduction to		&THIS.PLATFORM;		JAIN SLEE		&THIS.RA;		Resource Adaptor	</title>	<para>		This resource adaptor provides a MGCP API for JAIN SLEE		applications, adapting the JAIN MGCP specification - JSR 23.		JAIN MGCP is a Java specification for the Media Gateway Control		Protocol, as defined by the protocol specs done by the IETF		RFC3435.	</para>	<para>		MGCP assumes a connection model where the basic constructs are		endpoints and connections. Endpoints are sources and/or sinks of		data and can be physical or virtual.	</para>	<para>		Connections may be either point to point or multipoint. A point		to point connection is an association between two endpoints with		the purpose of transmitting data between these endpoints. Once		this association is established for both endpoints, data		transfer between these endpoints can take place. A multipoint		connection is established by connecting the endpoint to a		multipoint session.	</para>	<para>		Both endpoints and connection constructs are available to		support all type of MGCP Applications.	</para>
	<variablelist>		<varlistentry>			<term>Examples of Application using Connections are</term>			<listitem>				<para>					Transmission of audio packets using RTP and UDP over an					IP network.				</para>					<para>					Transmission of packets over an internal connection, for					example the TDM backplane or the interconnection bus of					a gateway. This is used, in particular, for "hairpin"					connections, connections that terminate in a gateway but					are immediately rerouted over the telephone network.				</para>			</listitem>		</varlistentry>			<varlistentry>			<term>Examples of Applications using Endpoints are</term>			<listitem>				<para>					An example of a virtual endpoint is an audio source in					an audio-content server.				</para>					<para>					An interface on a gateway that terminates a trunk					connected to a PSTN switch (e.g., Class 5, Class 4,					etc.). A gateway that terminates trunks is called a					trunking gateway.				</para>				<para>					An interface on a gateway that terminates an analog POTS					connection to a phone, key system, PBX, etc. A gateway					that terminates residential POTS lines (to phones) is					called a residential gateway.					</para>			</listitem>		</varlistentry>	</variablelist>	<para>		Events represent MGCP Request/Response received by the MGCP		stack, or failure use cases such as timeouts.	</para>	<para>		The Activities are the MGCP Connections and Endpoints, which		applications in the SLEE may use to send MGCP Requests and		Responses, and to receive the events related with incoming		Request/Response.	</para></chapter>