<?xml version='1.0'?>
<!DOCTYPE book PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "JAIN_SLEE_Example_User_Guide.ent">%BOOK_ENTITIES;]><chapter id="design_overview">	<title>Design Overview</title>	<para>		The example is designed to demonstrate the usage of JAIN MGCP		API including the MGCP RA. At the same time it also demonstrates		various features/capabilities of Mobicents Media Server. MGCP		messages are transmitted over UDP. Commands are sent to IP		addresses defined in the domain for the endpoint. The responses		are sent back to the source address (i.e., IP address and UDP		port number) of the commands. The domain name specified for		Endpoint can include port number as colon separated value. For		example 122.64.4.108:2427	</para>	<para>		When no port is specified for the endpoint, the commands by		default is sent:	</para>	<blockquote>		<para>			by the Call Agents, to the default MGCP port for gateways,			2427.		</para>		<para>			by the Gateways, to the default MGCP port for Call Agents,			2727.		</para>	</blockquote>	<para>		The MGCP RA bounds the MGCP Stack to IP address and Port		specified for jain.mgcp.IP_ADDRESS, jain.mgcp.PORT properties in		resource-adaptor-jar.xml for MGCP RA. For further details looks		at MGCP RA Documentation.	</para>	<section id="design">		<title>Design</title>		<para>The Example is composed of 3 Services.</para>		<blockquote>			<para>				First Service is composed of CallSbb as parent/root				listening for SIP INVITE as initial event. The IVRSbb and				RecorderSbb <!-- and TTSSbb  -->are its children.			</para>			<para>				Second Service is composed of only ConferenceSbb acting				as root. Its listening for SIP INVITE too and has lower				priority than above Service.			</para>			<para>				Third Service is composed of only ConfLegSbb acting as				root. Its listening for Custom Event fired by				ConferenceSbb when the first participant joins the				Conference.			</para>		</blockquote>		<para>			CallSbb listens for incoming SIP call and depending on To			field of INVITE it creates respective child; Child does			further processing of SIP Message.			<blockquote>				<para>					2010 : If user dialed 2010, IVRSbb child is created.					As name suggest IVRSbb is responsible for playing					announcement to user and listening for DTMF inputs					from user. Depending on which DTMF is dialed by					user, corresponding announcement is played again.				</para>				<para>
					2011 : If user dialed 2011, RecorderSbb child is
					created. As name suggest RecorderSbb is responsible
					for recording user's voice and playing it back after
					30 seconds.
				</para>
				<para>
					2012 : If user dialed 2012, CallSbb ignores message and relies task of
					creating ConferenceSbb to SLEE.
				</para>
								<!--<para>					2013 : If user dialed 2013, TTSSbb child is created.					TTSSbb sends the text to Mobicents Media Server					(MMS) and MMS plays back the speech corresponding to					this text to user.				</para>
				  -->			</blockquote>		</para>		<para>			ConferenceSbb is responsible for maintaining Conference.			User gets connected to Conference endpoint by dialing 2012			from SIP Phone. If this is the first User joining			Conference, ConferenceSbb fires Custom Event that is			consumed by ConfLegSbb. Multiple users can dial 2012 and get			connected to same Conference endpoint and participate in			conference call.		</para>		<para>			ConfLegSbb is acting as one of the automated leg of			Conference. As soon as conference is initiated, this leg of			conference will start a back ground music so even if there			is only one participant in conference he/she can listen to			music that verifies Conference has started.		</para>		<para>			As explained earlier, the main purpose of this demo is to			make developers understand how to use the MGCP API and MGCP			RA. Once there is clear understanding of MGCP API and RA,			the business logic can be written as required. Let us go to			Section 4, where MGCP usage from respective SBB is			explained.		</para>	</section></chapter>