<?xml version='1.0'?>
<!DOCTYPE book PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "User_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>

<section id="management_ere_top">
	<title>Monitoring JAIN SLEE Event Router Executors</title>
	
	<para>Event Router Executors are the heart of the JAIN SLEE Core, they are responsible for executing critical tasks for the container.</para>

	<para>In order to have a better view over the JAIN SLEE container health, a few metrics are made available in this section.</para>

	<section id="management_ere_summary">
		<title>View Event Router Executors Summary</title>
		<para>In the <guilabel>SUMMARY</guilabel> tab, some of the metrics for the executors are shown along with the corresponding graphs. Also, latest Out-of-Bound metrics and Alerts are displayed.</para>
		
		<figure>
			<title>&MANAGEMENT.PLATFORM; JAIN SLEE Event Router Executors Summary View.</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata width="300px" align="center" fileref="images/img-jopr_ere_summary_view.png" format="PNG"/>
				</imageobject>
				<textobject>
					<para>&MANAGEMENT.PLATFORM; JAIN SLEE Event Router Executors Summary View.</para>
				</textobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>
	</section>

	<section id="management_ere_metrics">
		<title>Monitor Event Router Executors metrics</title>
		<para>By accessing the <guilabel>MONITOR</guilabel> tab it's possible to see a lot of metrics for each executor:</para>

		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para><emphasis>Activities Mapped</emphasis>: Total activities mapped for all the event router executors</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><emphasis>Activities Mapped per Minute</emphasis>: Total activities mapped for all the event router executors</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><emphasis>Average Event Routing Time</emphasis>: Average time spent to route one event (in ms)</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><emphasis>Executed Tasks</emphasis>: Number of tasks executed, which is the sum of the events routed for each EventTypeID, and also the misc tasks executed</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><emphasis>Executed Tasks per Minute</emphasis>: Same as above, per minute</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><emphasis>Executing Time</emphasis>: Time spent on executing tasks, which is the sum of the time spent routing events for each EventTypeID, and also the time spent executing the misc tasks.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><emphasis>Executing Time per Minute</emphasis>: Same as above, per minute</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><emphasis>Idle Time</emphasis>: Total time the executor was idle, i.e., not executing tasks</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><emphasis>Idle Time per Minute</emphasis>: Same as above, per minute</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><emphasis>Misc Tasks Executed</emphasis>: Number of misc tasks executed</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><emphasis>Misc Tasks Executed per Minute</emphasis>: Same as above, per minute</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><emphasis>Misc Tasks Executing Time</emphasis>: Time spent executing misc tasks.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><emphasis>Misc Tasks Executing Time per Minute</emphasis>: Same as above, per minute</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		
		<para>This metrics can also be seen in a table, in the <guilabel>TABLES</guilabel> sub-menu, in <guilabel>MONITOR</guilabel> tab.</para>
		
		<note>
			<title>* per Minute Metrics</title>
			<para>The "... per Minute" metrics are calculated by &MANAGEMENT.PLATFORM; so, they may not be accurate for container lifetime, ie, they are based on values gathered while &MANAGEMENT.PLATFORM; agent is running.</para>
		</note>
		
		<para>It is possible to enable and disable metrics and also set the collection interval by accessing the <guilabel>SCHEDULES</guilabel> sub-menu, in <guilabel>MONITOR</guilabel> tab.</para>
	</section>
</section>
