<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!DOCTYPE book PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "User_Guide.ent">%BOOK_ENTITIES;]>

<chapter
	id="introduction">

	<title>Introduction to &THIS.PLATFORM; JAIN SLEE</title>

	<para><acronym>JAIN SLEE</acronym> is the specification for a Java Service Logic and Execution Environment (<acronym>SLEE</acronym>) architecture, done in Java Community Process (<acronym>JCP</acronym>) by several individuals and companies, including Red Hat. A <acronym>SLEE</acronym> is an application server, or service container, which defines a component model for structuring the logic of communications services as a collection of reusable components, and for composing these components into even more sophisticated services. This model was designed and optimized for event driven applications.</para>
	
	<para>In addition to the service component model, the <acronym>SLEE</acronym> also defines management interfaces used to administer the container and the service components executing within, and a set of standard facilities, which provides common features, such as timers, traces and alarms, to JAIN SLEE components.</para>
	
	<para>&THIS.PLATFORM; <acronym>JAIN SLEE</acronym> is the first and only open source platform certified for <acronym>JAIN SLEE</acronym> 1.1 compliance, providing a highly-scalable, event-driver application server with a robust component model and a fault-tolerant execution environment.</para>
	
	<mediaobject>
		<imageobject>
			<imagedata
				width="410"
				align="center"
				fileref="images/introduction-slee_and_jee.png"
				format="PNG"/>
		</imageobject>
		<caption>
			<para>Overview of &THIS.PLATFORM; JAIN SLEE</para>
		</caption>
	</mediaobject>
	
	<para>&THIS.PLATFORM; <acronym>JAIN SLEE</acronym> is built on top of the open source award winning &JEE.PLATFORM;, which means that &THIS.PLATFORM; <acronym>JAIN SLEE</acronym> complements <acronym>JAIN SLEE</acronym> with Java Enterprise (<acronym>JEE</acronym>) 5 container features, allowing strong convergence of different application models, for even feature richer communication services, for instance, the Web and <acronym>SIP</acronym> can be combined to achieve a more sophisticated and natural user experience. &THIS.PLATFORM; <acronym>JAIN SLEE</acronym> inherits quality management features and tools from &JEE.PLATFORM;, such as the JMX Console, &MANAGEMENT.PLATFORM; Plugins and SNMP Adaptor.</para>
	
	<mediaobject>
		<imageobject>
			<imagedata
				align="center"
				fileref="images/introduction-platform.png"
				format="PNG"/>
		</imageobject>
		<caption>
			<para>&THIS.PLATFORM; Platform</para>
		</caption>
	</mediaobject>
	
	<para>&THIS.PLATFORM; <acronym>JAIN SLEE</acronym> can also be complemented with &THIS.PLATFORM; <acronym>SIP Servlets</acronym> and &THIS.PLATFORM; <acronym>Media Server</acronym>, providing unique value and integration features not found elsewhere.</para>
	
</chapter>