<?xml version='1.0' encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
]><!-- chapter id nickname: itjss -->
<chapter id="itjss-Installing_the_JAIN_SLEE_Server">
	<title>Installing the JAIN SLEE Server</title>
	<para>The Mobicents JAIN SLEE Server can be installed by downloading the ready-to-go binary distribution</para>
	<para>Alternatively, the source code can be obtained using the Subversion version control system (<acronym>VCS</acronym>) and then can be built from source.  Installing the binary distribution is recommended for most users, and obtaining and building the source code distribution is recommended for those who want access to the latest revisions and capabilities.  This guide discusses how to install, run and configure the Mobicents JAIN SLEE Server from the ready-to-go binary distribution.</para>
	
	<xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="mob-task-section-Java_Development_Kit-Installing_Configuring_and_Running.xml"/>
	
	<section	id="itjss-binary-JAIN_SLEE_Server-Installing_Configuring_and_Running">
		<title>Binary Distribution: Installing, Configuring and Running</title>
		
		<section	id="itjss-binary-JAIN_SLEE_Server-PreInstall_Requirements_and_Prerequisites">
			<title>Pre-Install Requirements and Prerequisites</title>
			<para>Ensure that the following requirements have been met before continuing with the install.</para>
			<variablelist
				id="itjss-binary-JAIN_SLEE_Server-Hardware_Requirements">
				<title>Hardware Requirements</title>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>Sufficient Disk Space</term>
					<listitem><para>Once unzipped, the JAIN SLEE Server binary release requires <emphasis>at least</emphasis> &JSS_SIZE; of free disk space.  Keep in mind that disk space requirements may change from release to release.</para></listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>Anything Java Itself Will Run On</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>The Mobicents JAIN SLEE Server, its bundled servers, resource adapters, and demonstration examples are 100% java.. The JAIN SLEE Server will run on the same hardware that the JBoss Application Server runs on.</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
			</variablelist>
			<variablelist
				id="itjss-binary-JAIN_SLEE_Server-Software_Prerequisites">
				<title>Software Prerequisites</title>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>JDK 5 or Higher</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>A working installation of the Java Development Kit (<acronym>JDK</acronym>) version 5 or higher is required in order to run the Mobicents JAIN SLEE Server. Note that the JBoss Application Server is a runtime dependency of the JAIN SLEE Server and, as mentioned, comes bundled with the binary distribution.</para>
					<!--<para>For instructions on how to install the JDK, refer to <xref
							linkend="jdkicar-binary-Java_Development_Kit-Installing_Configuring_and_Running"/>.</para>-->
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
			</variablelist>
		</section>
		
		<section	id="itjss-binary-JAIN_SLEE_Server-Downloading">
			<title>Downloading</title>
			<para>If the server is going to be deployed into a production environment, it is recommended that the integrity of the zip file is verified.  If the server is being used for testing or evaluation purposes on a local machine, verification is not as important, but is recommended.</para>
			<procedure>
				<title>Downloading Without Verifying</title>
				<step>
				  <para>Open <ulink url="http://www.mobicents.org/jainsleedownload.html"/>.</para>
        </step>
        <step>
				  <para>The top row of the <literal>Files</literal> table holds the latest Stable (recommended) server version.  Click the <literal>Download</literal> link to start the download.</para>
        </step>
        <step>
				  <para>Click the zip file link to start the download.</para>
        </step>
			</procedure>
			<procedure>
				<title>Downloading and Verifying</title>
				<step>
				  <para>Open <ulink url="http://www.mobicents.org/jainsleedownload.html"/>.</para>
        </step>
        <step>
				  <para>The top row of the <literal>Files</literal> table holds the latest Stable (recommended) server version.  Click the <literal>Download</literal> link to start the download.</para>
        </step>
        <step>
					<para>Download both the zip file and its attendant SHA-1 file.  For example, to download the latest recommended JAIN SLEE Server version, select the following files:</para>
					<itemizedlist>
						<listitem><para>&JSS_ZIP;</para></listitem>
						<listitem><para>&JSS_ZIP;.sha1.asc</para></listitem>
					</itemizedlist>
				</step>
				<step>
					<para>Check the integrity of the zip file by analysing the SHA1 file using a checksum verification tool.  The following command-line tools are suggested to perform this task:</para>
					<itemizedlist>
						<listitem><para>Linux: <command>sha1sum</command></para></listitem>
						<listitem><para>Windows: <command>sha1sum.exe</command></para></listitem>
					</itemizedlist>
          <para>To learn the operation of each tool, consult the help documentation available for the specific tool.</para>
					<para>If the two checksums are identical, then the downloaded binary distribution zip file's integrity is assured, and it is safe to proceed with the installation.</para>
					<warning>
						<title>Mismatched Checksums</title>
						<para>If the checksums are <emphasis>not</emphasis> identical, the downloaded zip file may have been corrupted during download, or has been changed since it was last uploaded to the server.  Re-download the two files (the zip file and the SHA-1 file) and verify the file integrity again.</para>
						<para>If the second attempt at verification results in a mismatch, it could indicate a problem with the install file.  Contact the Mobicents team through the <ulink url="http://groups.google.com/group/mobicents-public/topics">public forum</ulink> for further advice.</para>
					</warning>
				</step>
			</procedure>
		</section>
		
		<section	id="itjss-binary-JAIN_SLEE_Server-Installing">
			<title>Installing</title>
			<para>Once the requirements and prerequisites have been met, the JAIN SLEE Server can be installed onto the system.  Follow the instructions below for the operating system on which the server will reside.</para>
			<procedure>
			<title>Installing the JAIN SLEE Server on Linux</title>
			<step>
					<para>Create a subdirectory to extract the files into.  For ease of identification, it is recommended that the version number of the binary is included in this directory name.</para>
					<screen>~]$ mkdir <quote>jss-&lt;version&gt;</quote></screen>
				</step>
				<step>
					<para>Move the downloaded zip file into the directory:</para>
					<screen>~]$ mv <quote>&JSS_ZIP;</quote> <quote>jss-&lt;version&gt;</quote></screen>
				</step>
				<step>
					<para>Move into the directory:</para>
					<screen>~]$ cd <quote>jss-&lt;version&gt;</quote></screen>
				</step>
				<step>
				<para>Extract the files into the current directory by executing one of the following commands.
				<itemizedlist>
          <listitem><para>Java: <screen>jss-&lt;version&gt;]$ jar -xvf <quote>&JSS_ZIP;</quote></screen></para></listitem>
				  <listitem><para>Linux: <screen>jss-&lt;version&gt;]$ unzip &quot;&JSS_ZIP;&quot;</screen></para></listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        <note><para>Alternatively, use <command>unzip</command> -d &lt;unzip_to_location&gt; to extract the zip file's contents to a location other than the current directory.</para></note>
				</para>
				</step>
				<step>
					<para>Consider deleting the archive, if free disk space is an issue.</para>
					<screen>ms-<replaceable>&lt;version&gt;</replaceable>]$ rm <quote>&JSS_ZIP;</quote></screen>
				</step>
			</procedure>
			<procedure>
				<title>Installing the JAIN SLEE Server Binary Distribution on Windows</title>
				<step>
					<para>For this procedure, it is assumed that the downloaded archive is saved in the <filename>My Downloads</filename> folder.</para>
				</step>
				<step>
				<para>Create a subfolder in <filename>My Downloads</filename> to extract the zip file's contents into.  For ease of identification, it is recommended that the version number of the binary is included in the folder name.  For example, <filename>jss-&lt;version&gt;</filename>.</para>
			</step>
			<step>
				<para>Extract the contents of the archive, specifying the destination folder as the one created in the previous step.</para>
      </step>
      <step>
        <para>Alternatively, execute the <command>jar -xvf</command> command to extract the binary distribution files from the zip archive.</para>
        <orderedlist>
          <listitem><para>Move the downloaded zip file from <filename>My Downloads</filename> to the folder created in the previous step.</para></listitem>
          <listitem><para>Open the Windows Command Prompt and navigate to the folder that contains the archive using the <command>cd</command> command</para></listitem>
          <listitem><para>Execute the <command>jar -xvf</command> command to extract the archive contents into the current folder.</para>
          <screen>C:&bsol;Users&bsol;&lt;user&gt;&bsol;My Downloads&bsol;jss-&lt;version&gt;&bsol;jar -xvf &quot;&JSS_ZIP;&quot;</screen>
          </listitem>
        </orderedlist>
      </step>
			<step>
				<para>It is recommended that the folder holding the MSS for JBoss files (in this example, the folder named <filename>mss-jboss-<replaceable>&lt;version&gt;</replaceable></filename>) is moved to a user-defined location for storing executable programs.  For example, the <filename>Program Files</filename> folder.</para>
			</step>
			<step>
				<para>Consider deleting the archive, if free disk space is an issue.</para>
				<screen>C:&bsol;Users&bsol;&lt;user&gt;&bsol;My Downloads&bsol;jss-&lt;version&gt;&bsol;delete &quot;&JSS_ZIP;&quot;</screen>
			</step>
			</procedure>
		</section>
	
    <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="mob-task-section-Setting_the_JBOSS_HOME_Environment_Variable.xml"></xi:include>

		<section	id="itjss-binary-JAIN_SLEE_Server-Running">
			<title>Running</title>
			<para>In the Linux terminal or Windows command prompt, the JAIN SLEE Server has started successfully if the last line of output is similar to the following (ending with <quote>Started in 25s:527ms</quote>):</para>
			<screen><![CDATA[16:29:15,442 INFO  [ManagementConsole] Mobicents Management Console initialized
16:29:15,551 INFO  [Http11Protocol] Starting Coyote HTTP/1.1 on http-127.0.0.1-8080
16:29:15,586 INFO  [AjpProtocol] Starting Coyote AJP/1.3 on ajp-127.0.0.1-8009
16:29:15,622 INFO  [Server] JBoss (MX MicroKernel) [4.2.2.GA (build: SVNTag=JBoss_4_2_2_GA date=200710221139)] Started in 25s:527ms]]></screen>
			
			<procedure>
				<title>Running the JAIN SLEE Server on Linux</title>
				<step>
				  <para>Change the working directory to installation directory (the one in which the zip file's contents was extracted to)</para>
				  <screen>downloads]$ cd &quot;jss-&lt;version&gt;&quot;</screen>
			  </step>
			  <step>
			  	<para>(Optional) Ensure that the <filename>bin/run.sh</filename> start script is executable.</para>
			  	<screen>jss-&lt;version&gt;]$ chmod +x bin/run.sh</screen>
			  </step>
		  	<step>
		  		<para>Execute the <filename>run.sh</filename> Bourne shell script.</para>
	  			<screen>jss-&lt;version&gt;]$ ./bin/run.sh</screen>
        </step>
	  	</procedure>
		  <note><para>Instead of executing the Bourne shell script to start the server, the <filename>run.jar</filename> executable Java archive can be executed from the <filename>bin</filename> directory:</para>
			<screen>jss-&lt;version&gt;]$ java -jar bin/run.jar</screen></note>
			<procedure>
		  	<title>Running the JAIN SLEE Server on <productname>Windows</productname></title>
	  		<step>
		  		<para>Using Windows Explorer, navigate to the <filename>bin</filename> subfolder in the installation directory.</para>
        </step>
		  	<step>
		  		<para>The preferred way to start the Media Server is from the Command Prompt.  The command line interface displays details of the startup process, including any problems encountered during the startup process.</para>
		  		<para>Open the Command Prompt via the <guilabel>Start</guilabel> menu and navigate to the correct folder:</para>
			  	<screen>C:&bsol;Users&bsol;&lt;user&gt;&bsol;My Downloads&gt; cd &quot;jss-&lt;version&gt;&quot;</screen>
		  	</step>
        <step>
         <para>Start the server by executing one of the following files:
         <itemizedlist>
           <listitem><para><filename>run.bat</filename> batch file:</para><screen>C:&bsol;Users&bsol;&lt;user&gt;&bsol;My Downloads&bsol;jss-&lt;version&gt;&gt;bin&bsol;run.bat</screen></listitem>
           <listitem><para><filename>run.jar</filename> executable Java archive:</para><screen>C:&bsol;Users&bsol;&lt;user&gt;My Downloads&bsol;jss-&lt;version&gt;&gt;java -jar bin&bsol;run.jar</screen></listitem>
          </itemizedlist>
          </para>
			  </step>
			</procedure>
			
		</section>
		
		<section	id="itjss-binary-JAIN_SLEE_Server-Using">
			<title>Using</title>
			<para>The JAIN SLEE Server can be observed and controlled using the Management Console, which is started along with the server.  Refer to <xref linkend="wwtjssmc-Working_with_the_JAIN_SLEE_Server_Management_Console"/> for detailed information regarding configuring the JAIN SLEE Server with the Management Console.</para>
		</section>
		
		<section	id="itjss-binary-JAIN_SLEE_Server-Stopping">
			<title>Stopping</title>
			<para>Detailed instructions for stopping the JAIN SLEE Server are given below, arranged by platform.  If the server is correctly stopped, the following three lines are displayed as the last output in the Linux terminal or Command Prompt:</para>
			<programlisting>16:44:29,745 INFO  [Server] Shutdown complete
Shutdown complete
Halting VM</programlisting>
			<procedure>
			  <title>Stopping the JAIN SLEE Server on Linux</title>
			  <step>
	  			<para>Change the working directory to the binary distribution's install directory.</para>
		  		<screen>~]$ cd &quot;jss-&lt;version&gt;&quot;</screen>
		  	</step>
		  	<step>
		  		<para>(Optional) Ensure that the bin/shutdown.sh start script is executable:</para>
	  			<screen>jss-&lt;version&gt;]$ chmod +x bin/shutdown.sh</screen>
	  		</step>
	  		<step>
		  		<para>Run the <filename>shutdown.sh</filename> executable Bourne shell script with the <option>-S</option> option (the short option for <option>--shutdown</option>) as a command line argument:</para>
		  		<screen>jss-&lt;version&gt;]$ ./bin/shutdown.sh -S</screen>
		  	</step>
      </procedure>
		  <note><para>The <filename>shutdown.jar</filename> executable Java archive with the <option>-S</option> option can also be used to shut down the server:</para>
      <screen>jss-&lt;version&gt;]$ java -jar bin/shutdown.jar -S</screen></note>
			<procedure>
			<title>Stopping the JAIN SLEE Server on Windows</title>
			  <step>
		  		<para>Stopping the JAIN SLEE Server on Windows consists of executing either the <filename>shutdown.bat</filename> or the <filename>shutdown.jar</filename> executable file in the <filename>bin</filename> subfolder of the JAIN SLEE Server binary distribution.  Ensure the <option>-S</option> option (the short option for <option>--shutdown</option>) is included in the command line argument.</para>
		  		<screen>C:&bsol;Users&bsol;&lt;user&gt;&bsol;My Downloads&bsol;jss-&lt;version&gt;&gt;bin&bsol;shutdown.bat -S</screen>
		  		<stepalternatives>
		  			<step>
			  			<para>The <filename>shutdown.jar</filename> executable Java archive with the <option>-S</option> option can also be used to shut down the server:</para>
		  				<screen>C:&bsol;Users&bsol;&lt;user&gt;&bsol;My Downloads&bsol;jss-&lt;version&gt;&gt;java -jar bin&bsol;shutdown.jar -S</screen>
		  			</step>
		  		</stepalternatives>
		  	</step>
		  </procedure>
		</section>
		
		<section	id="itjss-binary-JAIN_SLEE_Server-Testing">
			<title>Testing</title>
			<para>&nbsp;</para>
		</section>
		
		<section	id="itjss-binary-JAIN_SLEE_Server-Uninstalling">
			<title>Uninstalling</title>
			<para>To uninstall the JAIN SLEE Server, delete the directory containing the extracted binary distribution.</para>
		</section>
	</section>
</chapter>
