<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!DOCTYPE book PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "User_Guide.ent">%BOOK_ENTITIES;]><chapter id="introduction">	<title>		Introduction to		&THIS.PLATFORM;		JAIN SLEE		&THIS.RA;		Resource Adaptor	</title>	<para>		This resource adaptor provides a SMPP API for JAIN SLEE		applications, adapting the SMPP specification version 5.0.	</para>	<para>		The Short Message Peer to Peer (SMPP) protocol is an open,		industry standard protocol designed to provide a flexible data		communications interface for transfer of short message data		between a Message Center, such as a Short Message Service Centre		(SMSC), GSM Unstructured Supplementary Services Data (USSD)		Server or other type of Message Center and a SMS application		system, such as a WAP Proxy Server, EMail Gateway or other		Messaging Gateway.	</para>	<para>		Using the SMPP protocol, an SMS application system called the		External Short Message Entity (ESME) may initiate an application		layer connection with an SMSC over a TCP/IP network connection		and may then send short messages and receive short messages to		and from the SMSC respectively. The ESME may also query, cancel		or replace short messages using SMPP.	</para>	<variablelist>		<varlistentry>			<term>				SMPP supports a full featured set of two-way messaging				functions such as:			</term>			<listitem>				<para>					Transmit messages from an ESME to single or multiple					destinations via the SMSC				</para>				<para>					An ESME may receive messages via the SMSC from other					SME's (e.g. mobile stations).				</para>				<para>					Query the status of a short message stored on the					SMSC				</para>				<para>					Cancel or replace a short message stored on the SMSC				</para>				<para>					Send a registered short message (for which a					delivery receipt will be returned by the SMSC to the					message originator)				</para>				<para>Schedule the message delivery date and time</para>				<para>					Select the message mode, i.e. datagram or store and					forward				</para>				<para>					Set the delivery priority of the short message				</para>				<para>					Define the data coding type of the short message				</para>				<para>Set the short message validity period</para>				<para>					Associate a service type with each message e.g.					voice mail notification				</para>
				<para>
					Cell Broadcast Services
				</para>							</listitem>		</varlistentry>	</variablelist>	<para>		Events represent SMPP messages, or failure use cases such as		timeouts.	</para>	<para>		The Activities are the SMPP Transaction, which applications in		the SLEE may use to send SMPP message's and message responses,		and to receive the events related with incoming message or		message response.	</para></chapter>