<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!DOCTYPE book PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "User_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<chapter id="building_jainslee_resource_adaptors">
	<title>Building JAIN SLEE Resource Adaptors</title>
	<para>EclipSLEE provides means to create, edit and delete JAIN SLEE Resource Adaptors.</para>
	<section id="creating_a_jainslee_resource_adaptor">
		<title>Creating a JAIN SLEE Resource Adaptor</title>
		<para>
			To create a component it may be easier (but not mandatory) to first create a package to contain it. This package should be created as a child of the &lt;ra-module&gt;/src/main/java folder. To do this right-click on the src folder and select <menuchoice><guimenu>New</guimenu><guisubmenu>Package</guisubmenu></menuchoice>. Give the new package a name using the popup dialog (shown below).
			<figure>
				<title>Creating a new Package in Eclipse</title>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata width="100%" align="center" fileref="images/img-eclipslee_new_package.png" format="PNG"/>
					</imageobject>
					<textobject>
						<para>Creating a new Package in Eclipse</para>
					</textobject>
				</mediaobject>
			</figure>
			In case a new package is not created at this point, it can still be created in the Component wizard, but no validation is performed at that time, regarding the package naming conventions.
		</para>
		<para>
			To create a new JAIN SLEE Resource Adaptor, right-click on the created package (or the module entry if the package is not yet created) and choose <menuchoice><guimenu>New</guimenu><guisubmenu>Other ...</guisubmenu></menuchoice> as shown below.
			<figure>
				<title>Creating a new JAIN SLEE Component in EclipSLEE</title>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata width="100%" align="center" fileref="images/img-eclipslee_new_jainslee_component.png" format="PNG"/>
					</imageobject>
					<textobject>
						<para>Creating a new JAIN SLEE Component in EclipSLEE</para>
					</textobject>
				</mediaobject>
			</figure>
			A dialog should appear. Expand the <guilabel>JAIN SLEE</guilabel> item and choose <guilabel>JAIN SLEE Resource Adaptor</guilabel>. The dialog should now look like the following:
			<figure>
				<title>Creating a new JAIN SLEE Resource Adaptor in EclipSLEE</title>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata width="100%" align="center" fileref="images/img-eclipslee_new_jainslee_resource_adaptor.png" format="PNG"/>
					</imageobject>
					<textobject>
						<para>Creating a new JAIN SLEE Resource Adaptor in EclipSLEE</para>
					</textobject>
				</mediaobject>
			</figure>
			Click <guibutton>Next</guibutton> to get the following dialog:
			<figure>
				<title>Selecting the package and name for a new JAIN SLEE Resource Adaptor in EclipSLEE</title>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata width="100%" align="center" fileref="images/img-eclipslee_new_jainslee_resource_adaptor_name.png" format="PNG"/>
					</imageobject>
					<textobject>
						<para>Selecting the package and name for a new JAIN SLEE Resource Adaptor in EclipSLEE</para>
					</textobject>
				</mediaobject>
			</figure>
			The source folder and package dialogs will be completed if <menuchoice><guimenu>New</guimenu><guisubmenu>Other ...</guisubmenu></menuchoice> has been selected from right-clicking on a package. Otherwise it may need to be chosen by selecting <guibutton>Browse...</guibutton> and selecting the desired locations or typing it's name in the appropriate field and it will be created in the end.
		</para>
		<para>
			Name the Resource Adaptor; the name must end with "<filename>ResourceAdaptor.java</filename>". Then click <guibutton>Next</guibutton> to go to the component identity dialog, pictured below:
			<figure>
				<title>JAIN SLEE Component Identity dialog in EclipSLEE</title>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata width="100%" align="center" fileref="images/img-eclipslee_new_jainslee_resource_adaptor_identity.png" format="PNG"/>
					</imageobject>
					<textobject>
						<para>JAIN SLEE Component Identity dialog in EclipSLEE</para>
					</textobject>
				</mediaobject>
			</figure>
			The Name, Vendor and Version fields are mandatory and are used by the SLEE to identify the Resource Adaptor. The description field is optional, but strongly recommended to be completed to allow easy identification of the Resource Adaptor in future.
		</para>
		<para>
			After completing these fields click <guibutton>Next</guibutton> to specify the RA Types the Resource Adaptor implements.
		</para>
		<para>
			<figure>
				<title>JAIN SLEE Resource Adaptor RA Types selection in EclipSLEE</title>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata width="100%" align="center" fileref="images/img-eclipslee_new_jainslee_resource_adaptor_ratypes.png" format="PNG"/>
					</imageobject>
					<textobject>
						<para>JAIN SLEE Resource Adaptor RA Types selection in EclipSLEE</para>
					</textobject>
				</mediaobject>
			</figure>
			This dialog allows you to specify which RA Types this Resource Adaptor will implement. Select them from the top list (Available RA Types) by clicking <guibutton>Select RA Type</guibutton>. To remove them, select them from the bottom list (Selected RA Types) and click <guibutton>Deselect RA Type</guibutton>. When done, click <guibutton>Next</guibutton> to edit the Resource Adaptor Config Properties.
		</para>
		<para>
			<figure>
				<title>JAIN SLEE Resource Adaptor Config Properties definition in EclipSLEE</title>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata width="100%" align="center" fileref="images/img-eclipslee_new_jainslee_resource_adaptor_config_properties.png" format="PNG"/>
					</imageobject>
					<textobject>
						<para>JAIN SLEE Resource Adaptor Config Properties definition in EclipSLEE</para>
					</textobject>
				</mediaobject>
			</figure>
			Here, the Resource Adaptor's Config Properties can be set. Add a Config Property field by clicking on <guibutton>Add</guibutton> and writing it's name on the <guilabel>Name</guilabel> column, selecting the appropriate Java Type in the <guilabel>Type</guilabel> column and, this is optional, type a default value (if no value is to be set, delete the default <literal>?</literal> which is inserted) in the <guilabel>Default Value</guilabel> column. 
		</para>
		<para>
			In this same wizard page, it is possible to define whether this Resource Adaptor supports reconfiguration when in ACTIVE state by checking or leaving unchecked the <guibutton>This Resource Adaptor supports active reconfiguration</guibutton> checkbox.
		</para>
		<para>
			Once finished, click <guibutton>Finish</guibutton> to create the Resource Adaptor Type.
		</para>
		<note>
			<title>Skipping optional steps</title>
			<para><guibutton>Finish</guibutton> can be clicked at any point after setting the Resource Adaptor's identity if a skeleton Resource Adaptor is required. It is not necessary to complete each wizard page first.</para>
		</note>
		
		<para>
			The Resource Adaptor Java file, <filename>MobicentsDemoResourceAdaptor.java</filename> (plus the remaining interfaces and classes which were selected at the wizard) is created in the specified package and opened for editing in the workspace. The <filename>ra-jar.xml</filename> deployment descriptor is updated to reflect the new ratype or created if not already present. The resulting workspace can be seen below.
			<figure>
				<title>JAIN SLEE Resource Adaptor created in workspace using EclipSLEE</title>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata width="100%" align="center" fileref="images/img-eclipslee_new_jainslee_resource_adaptor_workspace.png" format="PNG"/>
					</imageobject>
					<textobject>
						<para>JAIN SLEE Resource Adaptor created in workspace using EclipSLEE</para>
					</textobject>
				</mediaobject>
			</figure>
		</para>
	</section>

	<section id="editing_a_jainslee_ra">
		<title>Editing a JAIN SLEE Resource Adaptor</title>
		<para>
			It is possible with EclipSLEE to edit existing components. When right-clicking in one of the JAIN SLEE Resource Adaptor classes a similar menu should be shown:
			<figure>
				<title>Editing a JAIN SLEE Resource Adaptor through class file</title>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata width="100%" align="center" fileref="images/img-eclipslee_edit_ra_class.png" format="PNG"/>
					</imageobject>
					<textobject>
						<para>Editing a JAIN SLEE Resource Adaptor through class file</para>
					</textobject>
				</mediaobject>
			</figure>
			It is also possible to edit by right-clicking on the resource-adaptor-jar.xml descriptor. In that case a sub-menu allowing to pick which Resource Adaptor to edit is shown:
			<figure>
				<title>Editing JAIN SLEE Resource Adaptors through XML descriptor</title>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata width="100%" align="center" fileref="images/img-eclipslee_edit_ra_xml.png" format="PNG"/>
					</imageobject>
					<textobject>
						<para>Editing JAIN SLEE Resource Adaptors through XML descriptor</para>
					</textobject>
				</mediaobject>
			</figure>
			After selecting the desired Resource Adaptor, the menu shown should be similar to the one presented when using the class file to edit.
		</para>
		<para>
			The following actions are available for a JAIN SLEE Resource Adaptor:
		</para>
		<section id="editing_a_jainslee_ra-identity">
			<title>Edit RA Identity</title>
			<para>
				This operation can be accessed by selecting <guilabel>Identity...</guilabel>. With this operation it is possible to change the JAIN SLEE Resource Adaptor identity (name, vendor, version) and it's description. The following dialog is presented:
			</para>
			<figure>
				<title>Editing JAIN SLEE Resource Adaptor Identity</title>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata width="100%" align="center" fileref="images/img-eclipslee_edit_ra_identity_dialog.png" format="PNG"/>
					</imageobject>
					<textobject>
						<para>Editing JAIN SLEE Resource Adaptor Identity</para>
					</textobject>
				</mediaobject>
			</figure>
			<important>
				<title>Other components are not updated!</title>
				<para>EclipSLEE does not automatically update other component descriptors in order to reflect such identity change, so it should be made manually.</para>
			</important>
		</section>
		<section id="editing_a_jainslee_ra-ratypes">
			<title>Edit RA Resource Adaptor Types</title>
			<para>
				This operation can be accessed by selecting <guilabel>Resource Adaptor Types...</guilabel>, which allows to change the Resource Adaptor Types being implemented by this RA. The following dialog is presented:
			</para>
			<figure>
				<title>Editing JAIN SLEE Resource Adaptor RA Types</title>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata width="100%" align="center" fileref="images/img-eclipslee_edit_ra_ratypes_dialog.png" format="PNG"/>
					</imageobject>
					<textobject>
						<para>Editing JAIN SLEE Resource Adaptor RA Types</para>
					</textobject>
				</mediaobject>
			</figure>
		</section>
		<section id="editing_a_jainslee_ra-config_properties">
			<title>Edit RA Config Properties</title>
			<para>
				This operation can be accessed by selecting <guilabel>Config Properties...</guilabel>, allowing to add new Config Properties to the Resource Adaptor or modify or remove the existing ones. The following dialog is presented:
			</para>
			<figure>
				<title>Editing JAIN SLEE Resource Adaptor Configuration Properties</title>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata width="100%" align="center" fileref="images/img-eclipslee_edit_ra_config_properties_dialog.png" format="PNG"/>
					</imageobject>
					<textobject>
						<para>Editing JAIN SLEE Resource Adaptor Configuration Properties</para>
					</textobject>
				</mediaobject>
			</figure>
		</section>
	</section>

	<section id="deleting_a_jainslee_ra">
		<title>Deleting a JAIN SLEE Resource Adaptor</title>
		<para>
			It is possible with EclipSLEE to delete existing components. Right-clicking in one of the JAIN SLEE Resource Adaptor classes or XML descriptor file (see <xref linkend="editing_a_jainslee_ra" />) and selecting the <guilabel>Delete</guilabel> option.
		</para>
		<para>
			A confirmation dialog similar to the following should be presented:
			<figure>
				<title>Deleting a JAIN SLEE Resource Adaptor confirmation dialog</title>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata width="100%" align="center" fileref="images/img-eclipslee_delete_ra_confirmation_dialog.png" format="PNG"/>
					</imageobject>
					<textobject>
						<para>Deleting a JAIN SLEE Resource Adaptor confirmation dialog</para>
					</textobject>
				</mediaobject>
			</figure>
		</para>
		<important>
			<title>Impossible to undo this operation!</title>
			<para>Deleting a component is an irreversible operation, so it should be used carefully.</para>
		</important>
	</section>
</chapter>

