<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!DOCTYPE book PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "../User_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>

<section id="ratype_ra_interface">

	<title>Resource Adaptor Interface</title>

	<para>The &THIS.RA; Resource Adaptor interface, of type <literal>org.mobicents.slee.resource.jdbc.JdbcResourceAdaptorSbbInterface</literal>, may be used by applications to create RA activities, and retrieve JDBC Connections, its interface is defined as follows:</para>
	
	<programlisting language="Java" role="JAVA">
		<![CDATA[
package org.mobicents.slee.resource.jdbc;

import java.sql.Connection;
import java.sql.SQLException;

import javax.slee.resource.ResourceAdaptorTypeID;

public interface JdbcResourceAdaptorSbbInterface {

	public static final ResourceAdaptorTypeID RATYPE_ID;
	
	public JdbcActivity createActivity();

	Connection getConnection() throws SQLException;

	Connection getConnection(String username, String password)
			throws SQLException;

}]]>
    </programlisting>
    
    <variablelist> 
    <varlistentry>
		<term>The <literal>createActivity()</literal> method:</term>
		<listitem>
			<para>Creates a new <literal>JdbcActivity</literal> instance.</para>
		</listitem>
	</varlistentry>
	<varlistentry>
		<term>The <literal>getConnection()</literal> method:</term>
		<listitem>
			<para>Retrieves a JDBC Connection, which may then be used to execute statements (prepared or not) synchronously. Note that applications must close the connection whenever it is not needed, failure to do so may result in no available JDBC Connections for additional application instances.</para>
		</listitem>
	</varlistentry>
	<varlistentry>
		<term>The <literal>getConnection(String, String)</literal> method:</term>
		<listitem>
			<para>Retrieves a JDBC Connection using username and password authentication, which may then be used to execute statements (prepared or not) synchronously. Note that applications must close the connection whenever it is not needed, failure to do so may result in no available JDBC Connections for additional application instances.</para>
		</listitem>
	</varlistentry>
	</variablelist>
	
	<para>The &THIS.RA; Resource Adaptor interface also exposes a static RATYPE_ID field, containing the <literal>ResourceAdaptorTypeID</literal> of the Resource Adaptor Type it belongs, which may be used to retrieve the factory instance using the <literal>SbbContextExt</literal> JAIN SLEE 1.1 extension.</para>     
	
</section>